# Bintang Jeremia **Tobing**

#### **Full Stack Web Developer**

Jalan Pelita 4 Gang Aman No 7, Medan - Indonesia +62 812 62845980 | hello@bintangtobing.com | www.bintangtobing.com

" If you afraid of failure, then you don't deserved to be successful."

# Summary \_

Hello I am Bintang Tobing, I am the first of three children. I am currently 22 years old. My career journey started in 2016 which was the year I graduated from high school. I love challenges and new things, and I currently call my own profession a full stack web developer. So I started programming on web development since 2015, and now I have 10+ sites with different systems on them. The biggest system I have ever built is an employee management system in the office, a problem reporting system, an online forum with a chat system with ajax and vue js programming. The biggest websites I have made are btsa.co.id, sarjanamalam.com, movith.id because they have their own systems and specifications

# Work Experience \_\_\_\_\_

### Infinity Solutions, PT Benua Solusi Teknologi

Chief Technology Officer & Full Stack Web Developer

Jakarta, Indonesia Mar 2019 - Present

- Design, implement, and develop a client project that already provides an initial description, a rough system, and an initial fee to be completed immediately.
- · Ensuring all web application systems from both the client project and the internal office run smoothly without any problems.
- · Ensure and maintain all mail servers from either the vps or the server run smoothly without any
- obstacles and without any viruses or intruders.
   Handling advanced security if there are hackers or suspicions on the system or server.
- Innovating, designing, and realizing possible ideas to help office systems and client systems make office operational performance easier.
- Come and provide consultation to customers if anyone asks or makes an appointment about the development of a website or server.

### BTSA LOGISTICS, PT Berlian Tangguh Sejahtera

IT Support & Full Stack Web Developer

Medan, Indonesia Sep 2018 - May 2019

- Ensure all hardware and software run smoothly from head office, branch offices, out of town offices.
- Complete the development of the ASCEND ERP application on the server that the developer continues to develop.
- Ensuring all networks between port vendors, airlines, fleets, and between all related offices are always connected to the server.
- Ensure a secure network at the internal office or external.
   Maintain, build, develop the system needed by the internal office on the official website system to date. (btsa.co.id)

#### PT Metro Interior Medan

Medan, Indonesia

IT Support & Full Stack Web Developer

Sep 2017 - Aug 2018

- Oversee the management and ensure the operation of all hardware, software at the head office and branch offices.
- Ensuring the smooth running of the automation system and server data for each office
- Ensure and provide unsupported networks in each branch shop.
- Creating, developing and maintaining a shop website from 0 to completion (interiorrumahku.id)

### **BPR NBP 18, PT Bank Perkreditan Rakyat**

Medan, Indonesia Mar 2017 - Sep 2017

IT Support & Full Stack Web Developer

• Oversee the management and ensure the operation of all hardware, software at the head office, cash offices and branch offices

- Ensuring the smooth running of the automation system and server data for each office
- Receive and follow up users on disturbances in the system.
- Perform routine system maintenance and inventory such as computers, CPUs, printers and others
- Ensure that the NBP Sys operational system runs smoothly according to the applicable system
- Create, manage and maintain the official website bprnbp 18, bprnbp18.co.id

# Certificates

#### International

2019 Front-End Web Development Quantum Degree - NEXT Academy

Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia

#### **Domestic**

edan, Indonesia
edan, Indonesia
edan, Indonesia
edan, Indonesia
e

# Organizations \_

**Sarjanamalam.**Founder & Chief Executive Operational

Medan, Indonesia

Jan 2020 - Present

The organization was formed at the very beginning when I continued my studies in 2018.

And I had the idea to find a solution because I found a problem in my environment. They are not focused on what they are learning, and when they want to open up business opportunities, there is no one to support them. So I took the initiative to create an organization that has a vision to help them through creating a separate platform.

Not only the platform, in the future maybe we will create an ecosystem that allows it to support all the needs of this platform.

Maybe we don't know when the platform will be released soon, but we are optimistic that the platform we designed will be able to help many people.

### Remaja Naposobulung HKBP Ressort Medan Utara

Chief Ressort Coordinator

Medan, Indonesia Aug 2019 - Aug 2020

What is meant by the northern field ressort is a combination of several HKBP churches in the area.

My job as the coordinator of HKBP Glugur in the North Medan HKBP Ressort is

- Ensure that every member who joins the organization 80% participates in the HKBP Ressort Medan Utara activities.
- Ensuring membership administration reports are always completed on time.
- Ensuring that activities related to the HKBP Glugur organization in the HKBP Ressort Medan Utara will run smoothly.

### Remaja Naposobulung HKBP GLUGUR

Medan, Indonesia

Chairman

Apr 2017 - May 2020

- Creating, designing, and managing each section so that all activities run according to the predetermined program.
- Manage the membership administration of all members who are members of the organization.
- Organize and manage the flow of financial expenses and income within the organization.
- Plan, determine and organize social service activities, among church members, and annual activities of the organization.
- Responsible for reporting every activity.

#### Remaja Naposobulung HKBP GLUGUR

Medan, Indonesia Apr 2015 - Jun 2017

Vice Chairman

- Manage the membership administration of all members who are members of the organization.
- Organize and manage the flow of financial expenses and income within the organization.
- Plan, determine and organize social service activities, among church members, and annual activities of the organization.
- · Responsible for reporting every activity

# **Educations**

### **Universitas Prima Indonesia**

Sistem Informasi, Ilmu Komunikasi dan Teknologi Informasi

Medan, Indonesia Sep 2019 - Today

# SMK Negeri 1 Percut Sei Tuan

Rekayasa Perangkat Lunak, Jurusan Komputer

Medan, Indonesia Jun 2013 - Jun 2016